Guide to the 1% for Peace/Business Partnership for Peace records, 1985-1993.
1% for Peace/Business Partnership for Peace records, 1985-1993.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
1% for Peace/Business Partnership for Peace records, 1985-1993.
4547
Business Partnership for Peace.
18 c.f.
Correspondence, records, subject files, financial and organizational records, and ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, records, subject files, financial and organizational records, records pertaining to the founding of 1% for Peace, letters received and queries, and ephemera.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
1% for Peace was founded in Ithaca (N.Y.) with direct assistance from Ben and Jerry's Ice Cream to promote the direction of 1% of the Defense Dept. budget to social causes. In January 1992, the group changed its name to Business Partnership for Peace and clarified its mission as a lobbying group for an alternative approach to national security issues. In 1993 the group officially merged with Businesses for Social Responsibility and moved its operations to Washington, DC.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, records, subject files, financial and organizational records, records pertaining to the founding of 1% for Peace, letters received and queries, and ephemera.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Business Partnership for Peace.; Ben & Jerry's (Firm)
Subjects:
Peace movements--New York (State); Peace--Societies, etc.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to the permission of donor.
CONTAINER LIST
- Subject files (Box 1-3)
- Subject files and notebooks (Box 4)
- Subject files (Box 5-7)
- Unsolicited query letters, requests for information in response to ice cream label notices (Box 8-9)
- Subject files (Box 10)
- Subject files and volunteer cards (Box 11)
- Business surveys and Board/Staff flip charts (Box 12)
- Subject files (Box 13-16)
- Hate mail, information on other organizations, ephemera t-shirts, pins, etc. (Box 17)
- Correspondence - publications - 1989 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Publications - 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Clippings, pamphlets, correspondence (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - 1980s (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - publications - 1980s (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Correspondence - publications (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
- Publications (Box 18, Folder 8)
- 1% For Peace Action Kits (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Web database (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Economic conversion (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Publications, action kits, publicity (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, publications - 1990s (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Television, proposals, letters to businesses - 1990s (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Correspondence - 1990s (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Publication - "Update" - 1989-1991 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Budgets - 1991-1993 (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Organizational development (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Photographs (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Publicity fundraiser event (Box 18, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, memoranda - Business Partnership for Peace (Box 18, Folder 21)
- 1% for Peace - Financial statements (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Correspondence - concerning donating money - 1992 (Box 18, Folder 23)
- Articles of incorporation - 1992 (Box 18, Folder 24)
- Merger (Box 18, Folder 25)
- Merger - legal accountant records (Box 18, Folder 26)
- Business for Social Responsibility financial records - 1992 - royalty agreement (Box 18, Folder 27)
- BSR - information (Box 18, Folder 28)
- 1% for Peace "Highlights" and "Updates" - 1991-1993 - financial records (Box 18, Folder 29)
- Merger - board discussion (Box 18, Folder 30)
- Merger - mission statement (Box 18, Folder 31)
- Merger documentation (Box 18, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, memoranda (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Brochures, reoganization memoranda (Box 18, Folder 34)
- Financial Reports and memoranda (Box 18, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, articles - 1988-1992 (Box 18, Folder 36)